<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-09-17T21:49:57-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Bradley Zhou</title><entry><title type="html">🖌 u&amp;amp;i</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/u&i/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="🖌 u&amp;i" /><published>2018-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/u&amp;i</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/u&amp;i/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bradley-z/bradley-z.github.io/master/assets/images/post_images/u&amp;amp;i.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was created for PennApps XVIII, which was my first “real” hackathon. Given our entire team’s experience with web development, we sought a way to expedite the front end design process. We also wanted a way to help those that are artistically gifted yet might not have the technical experience required for web work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;functionality&quot;&gt;Functionality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users draw the layout of a website on a sheet of paper. The user’s phone is positioned on top of the acrylic mount where the phone camera records each iteration of their sketch in real time, which is then translated directly to a live website, displayed on the user’s computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a mobile app created using React Native, our smartphone camera intermittently takes photos and sends them directly to a Flask API hosted on Heroku. This API then takes the image of the paper website layout and processes it and isolates each of its components using OpenCV. We then differentiate between each type of component, such as images and text, and reformat them to HTML. Finally, the rendered HTML is displayed live on the same website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ran into some problems pretty early on, when our desired hardware was no longer available. Our first plan was to use a Raspberry Pi to do the processing and its associated camera to capture the images, but there was only one camera available and it was quickly taken. We were then forced to pivot to using our smartphone cameras and an app to send images to a server to do the processing. Additionally, we were not able to send the images over UPenn’s wifi network, as it was not secure. We decided to send all the data using a cell service hotspot, which greatly limited our bandwith and image quality, which negatively impacted rendering results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team worked pretty well together, with each of us working on elements that we were already relatively familiar with, though we still found ourselves rushing to connect everything together in the last 8 or so hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CandiaGu/PennAppsF18&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://devpost.com/software/u-i-fqyz58&quot;&gt;Devpost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflection on Summer 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/summer2018-reflection/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflection on Summer 2018" /><published>2018-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/summer2018-reflection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/summer2018-reflection/">&lt;p&gt;As my freshman year summer comes to an end, I wanted to gather all my thoughts and experiences from the last few months and organize all of it as a way to keep track of personal growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;work&quot;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This summer, I had the opportunity to do materials science research at the Pittsburgh Supercomputing Center. Admittedly, I wasn’t initially ecstatic about the prospect of sitting in a room by myself for 6 hours a day learning about a topic that didn’t exactly align with my interests, but I quickly found my worries to be subverted. I was given a significant amount of freedom and was allowed to define my own project, so I decided to explore a topic that I was more interested in: machine learning. As an ECE major, ML isn’t in my usual curriculum and I didn’t plan on taking it until junior or senior year, so being exposed to it now was invaluable. Despite the whole experience being much more educational than I though anticipated, I also learned that research isn’t for me. While the freedom gave me choice in what topics I wanted to explore, it also offered little direction and guidance; I found that I much prefer having a well defined project and goal and I felt that I could accomplish much more if I had such guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travels&quot;&gt;Travels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start of the summer, I travelled to UIUC for two weeks for a high performance computing program as some kind of precursor to my research position. The purpose was for us students to be exposed to supercomputers and parallel computing before starting on our projects, but it ended up further reinforcing the idea that research wasn’t for me; with almost everyone else being MechE or Bio or Mat Sci majors, I was pretty much the only one with any kind of computer science background. And the material we went through reflected this, so I was a little discouraged for the first week or so. But after getting to know the other students, I started enjoying my time there a lot more. Also, since there’s absolutely nothing else to do in Illinois, I spent most of the free time I had rewriting my resume, updating my LinkedIn, and researching other opportunities; I actually found the Capital One program during this time and applied two days before the deadline. Overall, it actually turned out to be a pretty good use of time, meeting new people and being motivated to more establish myself professionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the middle of July, I went back to Long Island for a weekend for the first time since January, after which I moved to Pittsburgh permanently. While many people were away from home during the summer, seeing everyone that was home was amazing. I also got to go to the beach for the first time in a year, which was something that I actually wasn’t the biggest fan of when I still lived on LI. It was one of those things that I just took for granted and didn’t realize how much I’d miss until it wasn’t readily accessible at any time anymore. But feeling that sand on my feet again was definitely the highlight of the trip. Unfortunately, I didn’t get to go to the city, but I’ll definitely have more opportunities to go back there as opposed to LI, whereas this summer was pretty much the last time I would be able to easily see most of my friends from back home, as pessimistic as it sounds. But during the year, breaks rarely line up with everyone at different schools, and people are much more likely to be scattered during the summer at internships or summer endeavors after freshman year. And so as much as I enjoyed seeing everyone, I don’t really have that big a desire or intention of going back there anymore. Though I think that in the future, traveling to the big cities where people actually go to school will be much more appealing; visiting friends in places like Boston or LA seems tons more fun than going back to Smithtown and eating half apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very end of the summer, I went to DC (technically Arlington but close enough) for Capital One’s Software Engineering Summit Program. This actually turned out to be the highlight of my summer. In addition to learning about software topics like iOS/Android development, machine learning, and AWS, Capital One spoiled us so much. Between giving us beautiful hotel rooms to fancy meals to fun outings, Capital One did a really good job of enticing us to consider working there if we hadn’t considered it before. They even gifted us a bunch of tech at the end of the entire thing, too. The people I met there were also amazing. Despite the leaders at the summit being around ten years older than us, they did a really good job of connecting with us and by the end of only a few days, we were all really good friends with some of the leaders (some other students even took the liberty of affectionately calling one of them “mom”). The other students were also really personable while also sharing my enthusiasm for software. Funnily enough, four out of the 23 students were from CMU and I knew none of the other three before going there. It concluded with a hackathon, which was the first one I partook in, even if it was just a small one. While it wasn’t the greatest experience, it definitely did help me prepare for future hackathons and partner programming. I think the highlight of this trip was going in to DC proper for a night and being given free reign to do whatever we wanted. I really enjoyed spending the time to exploring and walking around Georgetown and the Waterfront by myself; I think during the summer, I began to find these times clarifying for the mind, but rare, and I wanted to take advantage of it. Also shoutout to the first Shake Shack I had since December; it was absolutely amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually didn’t imagine myself traveling this summer as much as I did. At the start, I was only planning on going to UIUC. But I’m glad I had the opportunities to travel elsewhere because honestly, they were the best parts of my summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal&quot;&gt;Personal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a lot of free time this summer to spend reflecting on my freshman year and especially about things that I wish I did differently and how I can apply my experiences moving forward; I saw this summer as an opportunity for maturation in all aspects of my life, whether it be academic, emotional, or spiritual. My religious life definitely saw the biggest improvement, however. Early on in the summer, I became more convicted to take it all more seriously, like going to church &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; Sunday and spending more time doing devotionals. I started to be harder on myself and get better at holding myself accountable. I’d also like to think this spiritual growth branched out into the other areas of my life that I sought to mature in. Emotional maturity was never my strongest area because it simply wasn’t something that I liked to talk about, but throughout this whole process, I’ve been learning more about myself and where my emotions come from and (hopefully) how to deal with them better. Academics and career goals also started becoming a bigger focus in my life. After taking 213 last semester, I gained a much better idea of what I actually wanted to do career-wise, and so I wanted to divert more energy into developing that this summer, too. It might be circular, but I think everything falls under the same umbrella of maturing as a person, and I’d like to think that that’s centered around spiritual growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This summer has actually been quite eventful, despite my initial apathy towards it, and has proved to be more eventful and much more of a learning experience than I expected. Particularly, I am happy with my personal development throughout the summer. Though I am happy with my progress and everything I’ve learned this summer, I’m far from perfect in all of those areas, but I’m excited to see what’s in store for next semester and how it all shapes out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">As my freshman year summer comes to an end, I wanted to gather all my thoughts and experiences from the last few months and organize all of it as a way to keep track of personal growth.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">💸 Pitch In</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/pitch-in/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="💸 Pitch In" /><published>2018-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/pitch-in</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/pitch-in/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bradley-z/bradley-z.github.io/master/assets/images/post_images/pitchin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital One’s Software Engineering Summit culminated in a hackathon where we were tasked with create something using &lt;a href=&quot;http://api.reimaginebanking.com/&quot;&gt;Nessie&lt;/a&gt;, Capital One’s hackathon API that emulates banking data. Our idea developed from problems we have ourselves faced in the past. Planning trips with friends can be a chore, especially with the finances; no one wants to be the one organizing everything. Creating a system where the finances surrounding a trip or event become centralized would greatly simplify planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;functionality&quot;&gt;Functionality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core functionality for our idea was a central API that would keep a track of all relevant data for all events, such as planned date, expected cost, and current contribution amount. This allows (in theory) for compatibility and synchronization across many devices and platforms, though we were only able to implement two in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;api&quot;&gt;API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The API extends Nessie with several new features, such as user logins, centralizing a third party account for travel funds, and issuing refunds. It was written using Flask-RESTful and is hosted by Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;messenger-bot&quot;&gt;Messenger Bot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every API feature was ported to a Messenger Bot, so a user can login and check his status simply through sending a message. Natural language processing recognizes different ways of writing statements with the same intent i.e. “How much money have we saved?” and “How much we got?” will both cause the bot to respond with the current progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;android-app&quot;&gt;Android App&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The API was also ported to Android, where a user can visualize all his planned events as well as view charts on group member contributions, adding a layer of accountability. Certain features, however, were not able to be ported in time, such as logins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first hackathon, even though it wasn’t a big one. I learned a lot about programming in a team setting. We faced several challenges, especially with Android SDK; one person’s computer kept crashing every time the app was built, HTTP requests took significantly more time to implement in Java, and merge conflicts were horrible with our inexperience with Android Studio. But overall, it was a good introduction for partner programming classes and future hackathons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bradley-z/PitchIn-API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bradley-z/PitchIn&quot;&gt;Messenger Webhook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">🖥 LILisp</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lilisp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="🖥 LILisp" /><published>2018-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lilisp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lilisp/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bradley-z/bradley-z.github.io/master/assets/images/post_images/lilisp.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Alt Text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project shared concepts with many of my previous assignments, namely 122’s Clac and C0VM, and 213’s Shell Lab. This project also served as a way for me to further explore my interest in systems programming. Additionally, much inspiration came from Daniel Holden’s book &lt;em&gt;Build Your Own Lisp&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;functionality&quot;&gt;Functionality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the Micro Parser Combinators library to automagically parse each input line into an abstract syntax tree. These were then converted into trees of what I defined as “lisp_vals,” which have one of many different types including numbers, symbols, or functions. Features of this implementation include builtin functions, user defined functions, recursion, loading files, conditionals, variables, mathematical and logical operations, and error handling. A more detailed list of functions can be found in the README &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bradley-z/LILisp/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was definitely one of those that demonstrated the beauty (and delicacy) of C. Like Malloc Lab, this project was littered with seg faults and pointer errors; one malloc call of the wrong size could break all my functions. But as someone who’s favorite lab was Malloc, I found working through these errors to be rewarding, albeit definitely frustrating at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bradley-z/LILisp&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">🎙️ gPodder Podcast Engine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gpodder-engine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="🎙️ gPodder Podcast Engine" /><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gpodder-engine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gpodder-engine/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bradley-z/bradley-z.github.io/master/assets/images/post_images/podcast_engine_one.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bradley-z/bradley-z.github.io/master/assets/images/post_images/podcast_engine_two.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital One’s Software Engineering Summit is a selective week long summit held at Capital One Labs just outside DC. This web app served as the final portion of the application to the summit and its purpose was to organize podcast subscriptions, visualize popular podcasts, and recommend new podcasts utilizing the API of a service called gPodder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;functionality&quot;&gt;Functionality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main frameworks used were Flask for the backend and Bootstrap for the frontend. Additional tools used include mygpoclient to access gPodder’s API, Requests to issue GET requests to other HTML pages, Beautiful Soup to parse such requests, thesauropod to generate recommendations, and Word Cloud to generate frequency visualizations. Features of this web app include search, listing subscriptions, searching by and within genre, suggesting what podcast one should listen to first, giving recommendations for new podcasts, data visualizations, and logins to view one’s own subscription data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was first issued this challenge, I was very intimidated; my experience with any kind of web development or even any project outside a class assignment was essentially none. In fact, it took me two or three days just to pick a framework to use. I also faced challenges with the API, given that it wasn’t very robust and I had no experience working with REST before. But once I picked a framework and started learning the basics, the rest was relatively repetitive. But overall, this one project taught me a lot about web development regardless of whether or not it was selected for the summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bradley-z/Capital-One-Mindsumo&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bradleyzhou-capital-one.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">🤖 HQ Helping Hand</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hq-helpinghand/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="🤖 HQ Helping Hand" /><published>2018-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hq-helpinghand</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hq-helpinghand/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bradley-z/bradley-z.github.io/master/assets/images/post_images/hq-helpinghand.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was one of the first projects I created outside of the classroom. The inspiration came from a time when a bunch of us were obsessed with the game and would play almost every day. Another online bot, HQuack, was shut down before any of us knew about it, so as a fun exercise, I decided to try and program my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;functionality&quot;&gt;Functionality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This program works by utilizing Tesseract OCR to extract the question and possible answers text from a screenshot. The program then uses Google Search API to search a formatted version of the question. Finally, the program iterates through the search results and returns the most probable answer from these results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This program’s inconvenience relegates it to more of a proof of concept than an actual practical tool during live games. After, all this was hacked together over the span of only about a day or two. But it does support the idea that search can be successfully automated within the ten second time frame. I’m sure that some more fine tuning and adding the ability to input live screenshots would make this actually practical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bradley-z/HQ-HelpingHand&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>